<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot on Giovanni Pavolini - Consultor</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot on Giovanni Pavolini - Consultor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Long to Wide and Wide to Long Format Conversion</title>
      <link>/blog/long-to-wide-and-wide-to-long-format-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/long-to-wide-and-wide-to-long-format-conversion/</guid>
      <description>¡Mirá una versión en español aquí!
One of the difficulties I find most often in Stack Overflow questions about R, an in general about data science, is the erroneous usage of wide formats for data analysis.
In this post we’ll se some functions of the data.table package in R to convert from wide to long format and vice versa.
Different Ways to Store the Same Data There are two possible ways of storing tabulated data: in a “wide” format, and in a “long” format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversión de formato Ancho a Largo y viceversa</title>
      <link>/blog/conversi%C3%B3n-de-formato-ancho-largo-y-viceversa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/conversi%C3%B3n-de-formato-ancho-largo-y-viceversa/</guid>
      <description>See an English version here!
Uno de las dificultades que con frecuencia encuentro en preguntas en Stack Overflow sobre R, y en general sobre ciencia de datos es la errónea utilización de formatos anchos de datos para análisis de datos.
En este post veremos algunas funciones del paquete data.table en R para convertir de formato ancho a largo y viceversa.
Diferentes Formas de Almacenar los Mismos Datos Hay dos posibles formas de almacenar información tabulada: en formato “ancho” y en formato “largo”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>